zubair ashfaque

Data Scientist / Machine Learning Engineer

System Analyst with 9+ years of experience in several industries. My journey from internet networks to neural networks is driven by my passion to learn. Looking to leverage my experience and knowledge as a Data scientist or Machine learning engineer at your company.



- 🔀 mianashfaque@gmail.com
- Lahore, Pakistan
- in linkedin.com/in/zubair-ashfaque-ab100621

- +923018480350
- zubairashfaque.github.io/
- github.com/zubairashfaque

WORK EXPERIENCE

System Analyst

Ja77

07/2017 - Present

Lahore

Jazz is a Pakistani mobile network and internet services provider Tasks

- Setting up Multi-Node Hadoop Cluster Hortonworks using Ambari.
- Data Ingestion from multiple sources using Sqoop Scripts.
 Shell Scripting creating automatized Shell Scripts for Sqoop, Hive, Spark.
- Perform complete database, operating system and application administration, ensuring 100% system availability for Revenue Assurance & Fraud Management platforms.

Contact: Muhammad Faizan Anwar – faizan.anwar@jazz.com.pk

Enterprise Application Integration (EAI) Planning

Jazz

Tasks

01/2017 - 07/2017

Islamabad

 Design, implementation, deployment, and maintenance of middleware architecture integrated with CRM (Siebel), Electronic Financial Inventory Control System (EFICS), Billing System (Geneva) and Provisioning System (Comptel).

Contact: Jalal Shahid - jalal.shahid@guest.jazz.com.pk

Broadband Supervisor

PTCL

2009 - 201

Lahor

PTCL provides telephone and internet services nationwide and is the backbone for the country's telecommunication infrastructure

Achievements/Tasks

 Configuring different ADSL routers & modems solving different problems regarding DSL and IPTV. Additional task was to develop and maintain the database of BCMS which was a complaint management system.

SKILLS

Data Science, Machine Learning, Python Programming, Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Convolution Neural Network, Artificial Neural Network, Artificial Intelligence (AI), Computer Vision, Natural Language Processing

PROGRAMMING

Python

PySpark

SQL

TensorFlow

Pytorch

Keras

EDUCATION

Bachelor in Telecom SystemsBeaconhouse National University

2005 - 2009

CERTIFICATIONS & COURSES

Deep Learning by deeplearning ai | Coursera

IBM AI Engineering by IBM | Coursera

Advanced Data Science with IBM | Coursera

Certified Data Scientist | DataCamp

TensorFlow in Practice by deeplearning ai | Coursera

SOFTWARE

IBM Cloud | I

Jupyter Notebook

IBM Watson Studio

Oracle RDB

Tableau

Anaconda

Zeppelin

Apache Spark

HADOOP

MACHINE LEARNING

Regression

Decision Tree

SVM

Naive Bayes

kNN

K-Means

Random Forest

Deep Learning